MANIKANDDAN GEDDY CHANDRASEKARAN

http://in.linkedin.com/in/manikanddangc https://manikanddan.github.io/mgc/ (Work in-Progress)

Eppertshausen, Germany

manikanddan.gc@gmail.com

+4915258753828 | Skype Id: gcmanikanddan1

7.5 years of experience in Digital Transformation Solutions working across various roles as Presales & Solutions Consultant, Product Management and Front-end Development. Blend of Software Engineering and Creative Design to reduce human machine gap by creating UX with optimum User Research techniques, Lean design principles and analytics driven UX improvements.

COMPETENCIES

UX: IA, Journey Maps, Wireframes, Prototypes, Usability Testing, Competitor Analysis, Personas, Experience Strategy, Content Strategy, Heuristics Evaluation, Analytics, A/B Testing, Lean UX, Design Sprints, Web / Mobile Design guidelines, Optimum User Research Techniques.

Tools: Adobe XD, Illustrator, Photoshop, Invision, Sketch, Principle, Framer, After Effects

Design & Lang.: Layout, Typography, Color Schema, UI Components, Animations, HTML, CSS, JS, JSON

HONORS & AWARDS

Won TCS Gem Points; 'On the Spot' award Path Breaker of the Year & Best New Entrant award (CTS) Brandon Hall Excellence Award & Best Project of the Year-2012 (CTS)

PUBLICATIONS

https://www.tcs.com/assuringmobility-for-the-internet-ofeverything https://www.tcs.com/blogauthors/manikanddangc

STARTUP

https://www.f6s.com/turuturu Selected as top 10 Proposals by one of State Governments in India assisted by WRI

EDUCATION

2018 - 2020 - M.A. Leadership in the Creative Industries Program, Hochschule Darmstadt University of Applied Sciences, Darmstadt, Germany

2006-2011 - M.S Software Engineering, VIT University, Vellore, India, 8.01 CGPA

EXPERIENCE

2014-2018 | Tata Consultancy Services (TCS), Chennai, India

Role: Product Strategy and Management – Created / Managed / Owned / Discovered

- Product Owner DOX
- UX Wireframes & Prototypes (iOS, Android, RWD)
- **Product Features and Product** Innovations
- Market Analysis and UX trends
- **Product Roadmaps**

- Product UX and Solution Model
- Product IA and role specific User Journey Maps
- Created Layout, Color Schema, UI controls, Typography
- User Research and Analytics
- Agile + Lean Execution

Role: Presales & Solutions Consultant - Presented / Owned / Managed / Published / Discovered

- Worked in esteemed TCS Customer **Experience Center**
- In-Person presentations to F500 Customers
- Usability Framework for Mobile Apps
- Architectural Consulting for Machine Learning driven TCS QET Products
- Context Mapping of QET Products in **Customer Environment**
- Innovated '5 Stars' User Reviews Mining Engine

2013 - 2014 | Photon Interactive, Chennai, India

Role: Presales and Solutions Consultant - Presented / Owned / Managed / Discovered

- Web and Mobile UX Consulting
- **Architectural Consulting**
- RWD, KIOSKs, Mobile, Wearables
- **UX Models for Industry Segments**
- **CRM Activities**

- RFP/I/Proactive Opportunities
- Wireframes and Mockups
- Click through Prototypes
- C-Level Stakeholders and Startup with Studio Environment
- Success Story and Case Study

2011-2013 | Cognizant Technology Solutions (CTS), Chennai, India

Role: Mobile App Developer – Developed / Managed / Learnt / Won

- Developed Animated UIs for iPad, Android and RWD Apps
- Agile Delivery Model

- Lifesciences, Healthcare, Manufacturing and Media Projects
- HTML / CSS / JS